Sparks Photographs
undated
temp2018-07-25T14:39
99 Linear feet
- Photographs, 1860-1997
  Series contains family photographs. The bulk of these materials include images of family members and locations in the Sparks area
  - Two story stone house, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_1; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a two story stone house. There is a small shed in front of the house.
    Photograph located in an album branded "The Cambrian Album," which contains vacation photos from Europe. Believed to be associated with Ella P. Hubbard, a possible travel companion of Maud Sparks.
  - Motorcar in front of a building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_2; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a motorcar driving in front of a two story building with a lot of windows.
  - Archway in a castle, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_3; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a stone archway in a castle.
  - Castle with a large turret, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_4; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a castle with a large round turret on the right side. There is a man entering a doorway into the castle.
  - Two stone castles with turrets, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_5; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of two stone castles each with turrets. There is a walkway between the two castles.
  - Wall and turret of a castle, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_6; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a stone castle's wall and turret.
  - Ruins of a cathedral next to a building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_7; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the ruins of a cathedral. Across the street from the ruins is a three story building. Between the two are three stone arches.
  - Stone arches, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_8; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of three stone arches. The arches are between the ruins of a cathedral and a three story building.
  - Round Chapel - Ludlow, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_9; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large round turret with an opening on each level. Caption on front: Round chapel - Ludlow.
  - Round Chapel - Ludlow, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_10; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large round turret known as the Round Chapel with an opening on each level. Caption on front: Ludlow.
  - Damaged square turret, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_11; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a square turret, part of Raglan Castle. The exterior of the wall next to the turret and the turret itself are both damaged.
  - Raglan Castle, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_12; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of an abandoned stone castle known as Raglan Castle. There is an entryway with a tree growing in front of it on the right side of the photo.
  - Roman ruins, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_13; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a wall with the bottom portion of columns on top of the wall. Caption on front: Roman Ruins.
  - Stone structure, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_14; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of an old stone structure. There appears to be a doorway at the base and windows near the top. The building appears to be partially collapsed.
  - Cows walking in the street, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_15; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of two cows walking across a street lined with two story buildings, one of which is a café. Behind the cows are some people in a wagon.
  - Norman church - France, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_16; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the steeple of a church. There is a small clock at the top of the steeple. Caption on front: Norman Church - France.
  - Chateau L'Anglais, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_17; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    The walls and a turret of the Chateau L'Anglais, located in Nice, France. Caption on front: Chateau L'Anglais.
  - Village street, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_18; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a curvy road with houses on either side. In the background is a steeple tower. Caption on front: Village.
  - Da Vinci's tomb, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_19; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a mausoleum covering the tomb of Leonardo Da Vinci. The mausoleum has a spiked tower at the top. Caption on front: L. Da Vinci's Tomb.
  - Four story brick building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_20; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large four story brick building. There is a turret visible behind the building and some smaller buildings to the right.
  - Gate at the Chateau Blois, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_21; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the gate at the Chateu Blois. There is a relief sculpture of a knight riding a horse above the gate and a couple of people walking through the gate. Caption on front: Gate - Chateau Blois.
  - Four story building with balconies, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_22; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large four story building. There is an entrance visible and prominent balconies on each floor above the entrance.
  - Chateau Blois, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_23; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Chateau Blois, a three story building with extended windows on the top floor and five chimneys visible. Caption on front: Chateau Blois.
  - Tower at Chateau Blois, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_24; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a four story tower at the Chateau Blois. The tower has a sloped roof and large windows on each level. Caption on front: Chateau Blois.
  - Large four story building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_25; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large building with four stories and towers throughout. Behind the building are other large buildings with towers. In the foreground are trees next to the large building.
  - Road leading to a large building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_26; Photographic print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph looking at a large building from behind a gate. There is a road leading to the building, which looks like a palace.
  - Milan Cathedral, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_27; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Milan Cathedral and the square in front of it. There are people walking through the square. Caption on front: Milan Cathedral.
  - Assizi building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_28; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a building in Assizi. There are three stories, with large archways and columns forming a covered walkway in front of the first story. Caption on front: Bldg in Assizi.
  - City square, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_29; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a city square with large three story buildings surrounding it.
  - Antiques store, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_30; Photographic print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a four story building. A sign above the first floor reads "Antiques 38 rue des changes." There are two cars parked in front of the building.
  - Peruggia fountain, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_31; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a fountain with a railing surrounding it. Behind the fountain are three and four story buildings. Caption on front: Fount. In Peruggia.
  - Assizi church court, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_32; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a courtyard in a church. There is a large entrance on the right as well as a staircase. Caption on front: Church Court - Assizi.
  - Bridge crossing a river, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_33; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a bridge with three arches crossing a river. In the background are three story buildings with many windows.
  - Monastery in Florence, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_34; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a monastery in Florence. The monastery is at the top of a hill and has an exterior wall with large buildings and a bell tower visible above the wall. Caption on front: Monastery - Florence.
  - View of St. Peter's in Rome, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_35; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a view from a window or balcony of Rome and the Vatican City. Visible in the image is St. Peter's Basilica. Caption on front: View of St. Peter's - Rome.
  - Roman Forum, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_36; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of Roman ruins. There is a grassy area with some damaged walls on one side and busts on pillars on the other side. Caption on front: Roman Forum.
  - Wall with a Roman sculpture, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_37; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a wall with a relief sculpture depicting men carrying tablets and rushing the Emperor Constantine. Caption on front: Burning the tax books before Constantine. Forum.
  - Tablet in the marketplace, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_38; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a tablet in the Roman market place. The tablet has relief sculptures of a pig, sheep, and cow on the side. Caption on front: Tablet in Market Place - Rome.
  - Arch of Tiberius, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_39; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Arch of Tiberius entering the Roman Forum. There is a stone covered plaza in front of the arch. Caption on front: Arch Tiberius - Forum.
  - Arch of Titus, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_40; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Arch of Titus leading to the Roman Forum. There are buildings in the distance behind the arch. Caption on front: Arch of Titus - Forum.
  - Roof of St. Angelo, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_41; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the roof of the Castel Sant'Angelo, also known as the Mausoleum of Hadrain, located in Rome. There is a sculpture of an angel holding a lance and a bell visible in the photo. Caption on front: Roof of St. Angelo.
  - Forum, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_42; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a stone archway showing a wire gate and some Roman columns with a damaged beam on top in the background. Caption on front: Forum.
  - Roman Colosseum, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_43; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Roman Colosseum. Caption on front: Colleseum - Rome.
  - Ruins at Ostia, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_44; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of some damaged walls and buildings in a grassy field. Caption on front: Ruins at Ostia.
  - Columns at the ruins of Ostia, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_45; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of two columns at Ostia. There is a wall with a partial archway next to one of the columns and a broken column in front of it. Caption on front: Ruins at Ostia.
  - Sculpture at Ostia, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_46; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a sculpture of a woman wearing a dress. She is missing her nose and an arm. Caption on front: Ostia.
  - Appian Way at Ostia, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_47; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a Roman road with columns and low walls on either side. Caption on front: Appian Way - Ostia.
  - Restored forum at Ostia, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_48; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the restored forum at Ostia. There is a large amphitheater with six columns at the front and a field of grass between the camera and the columns. Caption on front: Restored Forum - Ostia.
  - Borroccio's Equestrian in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_49; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a sculpture of an Equestrian ride created by Borroccio. There is a fence around the base of the statue and tall buildings in the background. Caption on front: Borroccio's Equestrian Venice.
  - Church on the Grand Canal in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_50; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large building with a dome and sculptures at the bass of the dome. There is an entrance with steps leading down to the canal, where there is a boat waiting. Caption on front: Church on Grand Canal Venice.
  - Canal in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_51; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a canal in Venice with tall buildings lining the canal. There is the dome of a church and a tall bell tower visible in this photo. On the water is a gondola and gondolier.
  - St. Mark's Square and Campanile, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_52; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of St. Mark's Square and St. Mark's Campanile. Thre are streetlights lining the square and a large three story building on the right. Caption on front: St. Marcks Square & Campanile.
  - St. Mark's Campanile from across a canal, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_53; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a view of St. Mark's Campanile from across a canal.
  - Venetian Customs House, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_54; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large canal with an old customs house visible on the right side. On the left are gondolas and small boats. Caption on front: Old Customs House.
  - Rialto Bridge in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_55; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Rialto Bridge crossing a canal in Venice. The bridge is covered with an ornate arch at the top. Caption on front: Rialto - Venice.
  - Rialto Bridge in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_56; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the Rialto Bridge in Venice. The perspective of the photo implies that the picture was taken looking up at the bridge from a gondola.
  - Houses on the Grand Canal in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_57; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of some houses on the Grand Canal of Venice, Italy. One is two stories high and the other is three stories with white trim around the windows. In the canal, a gondola is boat is carrying passengers. Caption on front: Houses on Grand Canal.
  - St. Mark's Church in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_58; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the front of St. Mark's Basilica in Venice, Italy. There are five large arches above doorways into the church and three visible domes on the roof of the church. There are people in the square in front of the church. Caption on front: St. Marks Church Venice.
  - Trades Building in Venice, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_59; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a Trades Building in Venice, Italy. The building has two stories with awnings supported by column arches. At the end is a three story square tower with windows on each level. Caption on front: Trades Bldg. - Venice.
  - Church, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_60; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large church with a steeple and bell tower on the left side of the church. There is a metal fence in the foreground of the photo.
  - Castle, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_61; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large castle with a entry gate visible. Above the gate are seven sculptures of people, possibly saints or past rulers. Above the sculpture are battlements with four turrets visible. There is a large road in front of the gate with a couple people walking across it.
  - Church, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_62; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Church with a large tower on the far side of the building, a rose window on the near side, and an exterior wall in front of a roundabout. There is a car parked on the roundabout.
  - View of a city, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_63; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    View overlooking a city. There are many buildings which look like houses with shingle roofs and a tower visible on the right side of the photo.
  - Two story house, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_64; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a two story house with a balcony wrapping around the second floor. The balcony is supported by vine covered columns.
  - Exterior of a house, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_65; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a home with a shingle roof. There is a lower first level, a turret on the right side of the phoot, and a small tower behind the first level. There is a courtyard with bushes in front of the house.
  - Wooden door, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_66; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a wooden door with a smaller servant door built into it. Above the door is a relief sculpture depicting a night surrounded by what looks like family crests, olive branches, and a ribbon.
  - View of a city, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_67; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    View of a city with some buildings in the foreground outside of the city walls. The city walls have turrets spaced along the wall and the buildings inside look like houses. In the distance appears to be a cathedral or large palace.
  - Ox-driven cart inside of walls, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_68; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a person driving a cart being pulled by two oxen along a road inside of a large wall which may be city walls. There are turrets every fifty feet or so along the wall. There is a large pile of debris next to the wall.
  - Square building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_69; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a square tower like building with small battlements at the top. There is an arch entrance at the base and five windows visible in the wall of the building.
  - Entrance to a cathedral, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_70; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of an entrance to a cathedral. The arch around the doors is ridged and the are relief sculptures above the arch. There are two men standing in front of the doors, one of which is partially open.
  - Wooden shed behind walls, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_71; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a single story wooden building inside of some walls, possibly city walls. The wall has turrets spaced regularly along the wall. There is a telephone pole and a tree next to the building. In the foreground are thin trunks.
  - Obelisk, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_72; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of an obelisk surrounded by trees. There are some tall buildings, one of which may be a cathedral, in the background.
  - Raglan Castle, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_73; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of an abandoned stone castle known as Raglan Castle. There is an entryway with a tree growing in front of it on the right side of the photo. Caption on front: Raglan Castle.
  - Round Chapel - Ludlow, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_74; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large round turret known as the Round Chapel with an opening on each level.
  - Building tower, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_75; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a building with a sloped roof at the top of one corner of a building, implying an attic or tower of some sort.
  - Damaged house on a road, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_76; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a damaged house next to a city street. There are some empty windows and areas where the wall needs to be resurfaced. There is a ladder leaning against the right side of the building.
  - Metal bridge, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_77; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a metal bridge with support beams extending from the structure of the bridge in a diamond shape.
  - Waterfalls, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_78; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large waterfall level with where the water falls over the edge. There is a road and some grassy areas in the foreground before the waterfall. The waterfall is curved, making it possibly Niagara Falls.
  - Snow covered mountains, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_79; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of snow covered mountains with some hills and slopes in the middle ground.
  - Forest, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_80; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a field which leads to a small forest of trees. Behind the trees, the steeple of a church is visible and there are hills in the background.
  - Road by a river, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_81; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of some construction or repair equipment on a road next to a river. There are some people crouching or walking by the river.
  - Arches overlooking the water, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_82; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a roundabout with a sculpture consisting of three arches and statues at the end of the roundabout. There is a railing around the sculpture, and the roundabout is overlooking a body of water where boats are docked. There is a building in the distance on the right.
  - Car being moved by a crane, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_83; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a car being moved with a crane onto a boat deck. There is a person in front of the car directing where it should go. There is another boat sailing visible in the background. Caption on front: Dover.
  - Fountain and large roads, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_84; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a fountain in a large circular pond. There are wide roads leading toward the fountain. On either side of the roads are grassy areas and wooded areas.
  - Chateau Chinon, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_85; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a partial standing wall of the Chateau Chinon. There appears to be a part of an exterior awning and balcony visible. There is a person standing on a footpath by the wall. Caption on front: Chateau Chinon.
  - Four story building, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_86; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large four story building with some extensions on the fourth floor and a tower on the right side of the building. There are trees growing in the foreground of the photo.
  - Tower of an abandoned castle, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_87; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a large oval shaped tower. There are four windows visible in the side and some damaged walls extending from the lower portion. There is a walkway coming from the base of the tower, along which a man and woman are walking. No identification.
  - Jean D'Arc's Room, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_88; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a dilapidated circular tower with a damaged balcony visible. There is a walkway shated by some trees going toward the tower. Caption on front: Jean D'Arc's room.
  - White cliffs of Dover, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_89; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of the white cliffs of Dover from a boat on the water. The sky appears to be overcast.
  - Three story brick house, 1900-1910; UNRS-P2017-13_90; Photographic Print; 2 x 4 (Box 10)
    Photograph of a three story brick house with a garage on the lowest level and the front entrance on the second level. There is a car with a spare tire attached to the back parked in the driveway.
  - John Sparks, 1871-1881; UNRS-P2017-13_91; Cabinet Card; 4 1/8 x 6 3/8 (Box 8)
    A cabinet card portrait of John Sparks taken in Cheyenne, Wyoming. Photograph done by Kirkland Studio.
    Removed from object 01881 and sleeved for ease of access.
  - Dr. David F. Knight, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_92; Cabinet Card; 4 1/4 x 6 3/8 (Box 8)
    A cabinet card portrait of Dr. David F. Knight, Rachel and Nancy Elnora Knight's father. He has a long face with white hair and a white beard. Photograph taken by Wilcox and Chapman Studio.
    There are two copies of this cabinet card. Copy 2: Handwritten on verso: Dr. David Knight Grandma Sparks father. Copy 2 was found in an envelope addressed to: Jno. Sparks Georgetown Tx.
    Copy 1 removed from object 01881 and sleeved for ease of access.
  - Maud Sparks, 1875-1885; UNRS-P2017-13_93; Cabinet card; 4 1/4 x 6 3/8 (Box 8)